<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CBC Opinion on Andrew Leach</title>
    <link>/opinion_bak/cbc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CBC Opinion on Andrew Leach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/opinion_bak/cbc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How the inspiration for Jason Kenney&#39;s inquiry into un-Albertan activities came to be so (mis)understood</title>
      <link>/opinion_bak/cbc/krause/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opinion_bak/cbc/krause/</guid>
      <description>Vivian Krause, the erstwhile detective who inspired Premier Jason Kenney&amp;rsquo;s beleaguered inquiry into un-Albertan activities, was back in the news this week.
A series of Twitter posts seemed to cast doubt on what many have assumed was her narrative all along: that U.S. commercial interests were somehow behind the now-infamous Tar Sands Campaign to slow or halt development of Alberta&amp;rsquo;s oilsands.
And yet, Krause was emphatic that no such narrative was ever present in her work, as tempting as such a link might be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. climate summit: Canada needs new and better policies, not another round of target bingo</title>
      <link>/opinion_bak/cbc/new_target/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opinion_bak/cbc/new_target/</guid>
      <description>Matching the U.S. on emissions reduction targets rather than policies has proved to be the undoing of many a Canadian prime minister when it comes to climate change. Prime Minister Justin Trudeau must understand why before his appearance at this week&amp;rsquo;s U.S. climate summit.
The fundamental problem with agreeing to reduce our emissions by the same percentage as the U.S. relative to some historic year (say, 50 per cent below 2005 levels by 2030) is that we&amp;rsquo;d require more stringent policies to reach that outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
