<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CBC Opinion on Andrew Leach</title>
    <link>/opinion/cbc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CBC Opinion on Andrew Leach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/opinion/cbc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Danielle Smith has a big idea to clean up oil and gas wells. It&#39;s all kinds of messy</title>
      <link>/opinion/cbc/r_star/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opinion/cbc/r_star/</guid>
      <description>In a July 2021 op-ed in the Calgary Herald, Danielle Smith, then a business lobbyist with the Alberta Enterprise Group, advocated for a program called R-Star. It would provide royalty credits to oil and gas companies completing cleanup activities already required of them. While it appeared for a long time to be dead, R-Star has new life.
Smith is now Alberta premier, and continues to champion the idea. Peter Guthrie, her new energy minister, promised to make a pilot of the scheme one of his first priorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Jasons Kenney of the past would thunder over Alberta&#39;s &#39;Bitumen Boondoggle&#39;</title>
      <link>/opinion/cbc/jasons_kenney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opinion/cbc/jasons_kenney/</guid>
      <description>Alberta Premier Jason Kenney has done many things in government that would come as a great surprise to the Jasons Kenney of the past, but perhaps none so much as the decision to purchase a 50 per cent interest in the Sturgeon Refinery.
According to Energy Minister Sonya Savage, the near-billion-dollar deal was the best we could hope for as taxpayers, seeing as it would limit ongoing losses to the public purse from the deal on the refinery, located 45 kilometres northeast of Edmonton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the inspiration for Jason Kenney&#39;s inquiry into un-Albertan activities came to be so (mis)understood</title>
      <link>/opinion/cbc/krause/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opinion/cbc/krause/</guid>
      <description>Vivian Krause, the erstwhile detective who inspired Premier Jason Kenney&amp;rsquo;s beleaguered inquiry into un-Albertan activities, was back in the news this week.
A series of Twitter posts seemed to cast doubt on what many have assumed was her narrative all along: that U.S. commercial interests were somehow behind the now-infamous Tar Sands Campaign to slow or halt development of Alberta&amp;rsquo;s oilsands.
And yet, Krause was emphatic that no such narrative was ever present in her work, as tempting as such a link might be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. climate summit: Canada needs new and better policies, not another round of target bingo</title>
      <link>/opinion/cbc/new_target/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opinion/cbc/new_target/</guid>
      <description>Matching the U.S. on emissions reduction targets rather than policies has proved to be the undoing of many a Canadian prime minister when it comes to climate change. Prime Minister Justin Trudeau must understand why before his appearance at this week&amp;rsquo;s U.S. climate summit.
The fundamental problem with agreeing to reduce our emissions by the same percentage as the U.S. relative to some historic year (say, 50 per cent below 2005 levels by 2030) is that we&amp;rsquo;d require more stringent policies to reach that outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
